Connor Lewis-Smith

ConnorLewisSmith@gmail.com 4545 Sand Point Way NE, APT #203, Seattle, WA 98105 (206) 948-8360

PROFILE

Currently studying fishing community characteristics to inform management decisions as a Data Management Specialist with the Pacific States Marine Fisheries Commission in support of NOAA Fisheries Conservation Biology for the West Coast.

Demonstrated passion for data management and analysis through both coursework and graduate research assistantships ranging in topics from lidar, domoic acid, fisheries participation data, and salmon restoration. Recent graduate from the University of Washington with a Masters in Marine Affairs and a Graduate Certification in Climate Science.

Extensive coordinating and management experience gained through four summers teaching student programs at the Woodland Park Zoo, college level teaching assistant positions, and four more years leading and managing operations for the active travel company Backroads.

Avid student in the richness of the world's cultural diversity demonstrated through travels to over 30 different countries. Conversant in Spanish and proficient in Arabic. Driven to create an inclusive work environment.

EXPERIENCE

Data Management Specialist, Pacific States Marine Fisheries Commission, 5/2022 – current

- Developed, maintained, and distributed relational databases concerning fishing communities to contribute to the California Current Ecosystems Assessment and Coastal Community Snapshots in support of the NOAA Fisheries Conservation Biology Office.
- Managing the creation of social indicators for West Coast recreational fishing communities.
- Researching fishing community risk mitigation with data from the NOAA West Coast Fishery Participation surveys.

Graduate Research Assistant, University of Washington, 6/2021 – 8/2022

- Created high quality summaries, figures, statistical reports, and static maps for a range of customized data on topics ranging from domoic acid, fisheries landings, fisheries participation survey responses, and fish barrier inventories.
- Compiled and organized spatial datasets from diverse sources to produce a qualitative comparison of fish barrier prioritization indexes.
- Produced an online interactive map application for the public to view survey results aggregated to broad spatial scales.

Staff Member, The Avid Angler, 9/2020 – 6/2021

• Engaged customers with unique insights into recreational fishing in Western Washington

Reader-Grader, University of Washington, 10/2020 – 6/2021

Graded guizzes, sustainability activities, and exams for over 70 students each academic guarter

Trip Leader and Manager/Operations Expert, Backroads, 6/2016 – 7/2020

- Organized and led highly regarded outdoor adventure trips across western US
- Solved dynamic issues related to regional equipment, staff housing, and guest services
- Developed expertise in environmental and social issues in over 8 regions to educate clients
- Authored global information packets as part of a writing team
- High performance led to promotions from trip prep specialist to trip leader, to regional manager/operations expert of the Southwestern United States

Connor Lewis-Smith

Page Two

Lead Undergraduate Researcher, 9/2015 – 5/2016

- Founded research section with Dr. Elizabeth Braker to study the distribution of native bees on Occidental College's campus.
- Trained student team conducting samples and identification

Teaching Assistant, Occidental College, 9/2015 – 5/2016

- Invited to support faculty in teaching introductory environmental biology courses for two semesters
- Provided in class guidance and clarification regarding data entry

Instructor, Woodland Park Zoo, summers of 2011, 2012, 2013, and 2014

- Promoted from intern, to assistant, to instructor
- Provided unique educational opportunities for children ages three to 14
- Mentored teen volunteers and program assistants while aiding them in developing teaching and group management skills

EDUCATION

University of Washington, School of Marine and Environmental Affairs, Seattle, 2020 - 2022

- Masters of Marine Affairs, Thesis Advisee of Dr. Sunny Jardine
- Graduate Certificate in Climate Science

Occidental College, Los Angeles, 2012 - 2016

- Biology Major
- Cum Laude
- Member, Dean's list

American University of Sharjah, United Arab Emirates, 2/2015-6/2015

Extensive cultural immersion

AWARDS

Jay Ginter Memorial Scholarship Fund, University of Washington, 2021

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

- Proficient/Advanced level with R and Git
- Intermediate level with HTML, CSS, Python, and SQL